Guide to the Duncan McNaughton Papers M1459
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Duncan McNaughton papers
1973-1993
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
McNaughton, Duncan
M1459
20 Linear Feet (41 boxes)
Correspondence and writing from poet, publisher, educator & critic Duncan McNaughton.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2005 and 2008.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Duncan McNaughton is an American poet, scholar, cultural critic, small press editor, and a founder/publisher of several seminal magazines. McNaughton also established the Poetics Program at the New College of California in San Francisco and directed the program from its opening in 1965 until 1990. The Collection contains manuscripts, notebooks, correspondence, and material concerning the New College.
Poets, American -- 20th century; American literature -- 20th century.; McNaughton, Duncan
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: Incoming Correspondence
    - Richard Aaron (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Steve Abbott (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Etel Adnan (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Arts + Letters (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ammiel Alcalay (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Donald Allen (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gordon Baldwin (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Christopher Bamford (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Amiri Baraka (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ron Barnard (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bill Barrett (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dawn Michelle Baude (Dawn Kolokithas) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Charles G. Bell (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Franco Beltrametti, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Franco Beltrametti, empty envelopes (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Giona Beltrametti (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Marco Beltrametti (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Peter Berg (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Carol Berge (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bill Berkson (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Lucia Berlin, 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lucia Berlin, 1999-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ted Berrigan (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bezoar (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Julien Blaine (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Robin Blaser (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Magda Bogin (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Joe Brainard (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Stan Brakhage (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kate Braveman (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - David Bromige (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bob Brooks (Curbstone Press) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bill Brown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Harvey Brown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Maggie Brown (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Michael Brownstein (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Paul Buck (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Avery E. D. Burns (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Collette Marie Butterick (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - George Butterick, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - George Butterick, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Michael Bylebyl (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - B's - unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Douglas Calhoun (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bob Callahan (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Callaloo: A Journalist of African-American + African Arts + Letters (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sophie Calle (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ronald Caplan (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Jean-Marie Carroll (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Lee Chapman (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Ann Charters (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Tom Clark (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - John Clarke, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - John Clarke, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - John Clarke, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - John Clarke, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - John Clarke, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - John Clarke, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - John Clarke, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - John Clarke, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - John Clarke, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - John Clarke, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - John Clarke, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Andrei Codrescu (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Henry Cole (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Robert Commanday (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Michael Coffey (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Norma Cole (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Jess [Collins] (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jack Collom (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Julia Connor (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - William Corbett (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Eileen Corder (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cid Corman (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Pierre Coupey (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Robert Creeley, June 26, 1976 (includes Inscribed Typescript of "Hello") (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Robert Creeley, 1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Robert Creeley, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Robert Creeley 1990-2002 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Robert Creeley undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Andrew Crozier (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - John Daley (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Chris Daniels (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Michael Davidson (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Alan Davies (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Fielding Dawson (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Steve Dickison (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Diane Diprima (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Ed Dorn (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Helene Dorn (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Jenny Dorn (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Nathaniel Dorsky ("Nick") (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Peter Downsbrough, 1974-1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Peter Downsbrough, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Peter Downsbrough, 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Peter Downsbrough, 1996-2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Karen Driscoll (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Patrick Doud (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Richard Duerdon (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Robert Duncan (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Lawrence Durell (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "D" Unknown (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Larry Eigner (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Aziz Elhihi (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Stephen Ellis (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Stephen Emerson (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Larry Fagin (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Simone Fattal (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Brian Fawcett (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Vincent Ferrini (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Rita Fink (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Alec Finlay (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Christina Fisher (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Michael Fournier (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Leonard Fox (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Raymond Foye (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Benjamin Friedlander (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Nemi Frost (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dick Gallup (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Dwight Gardiner (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Drew Gardner (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Christopher Gaynor (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Larry Gilmore (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Allen Ginsberg (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ariella Givlivi (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Peter Gizzi (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover 1991-2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Albert [Mike] Glover undetermined date (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - John Godfrey (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mike Goldberg (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mary Greer (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Donald Guravich (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Jim Gusafson (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - David Hadbawnik (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Drummond Hadley (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Terrel Hale (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Steven Hall (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mac Hammond (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Carl Harrison-Ford (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Bobbie L. Hawkins (Creeley) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Lyn Hejinian (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Kris Hemensley (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Dale Herd (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Leland Hickman (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Andrew Hill (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Jack Hirschman (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Emmanuel Hocguard (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Bob Hogg (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Gad Hollander (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Anselm Hollo (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Lindy Hough (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Susan Howe (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Stefan Hyner, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Stefan Hyner, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Stefan Hyner, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Stefan Hyner, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Kenneth Irby, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Kenneth Irby, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Kenneth Irby, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kenneth Irby, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Roderick Iverson, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Roderick Iverson, ca. 1998 (w/ original poem) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Roderick Iverson, 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Roderick Iverson, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - John James (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Lisa Jarnot (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Salvador Jimenez-Fajardo (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Kent Johnson (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Alastair Johnston (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Steve Jonas (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pierre Joris (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Mary Julia (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Howard Junker (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Paul Kahn (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Lawrence Kearney (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Robert Kelly (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Stella Kerouac (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Kevin Killian (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Edward Kissam (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Jay Knoepfel (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Michael Kohler (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Marianne Kolb (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Jim Koller (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Dawn Kolokithas (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Joanne + Donald Kyger (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Steve Lacy (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Gerrit Lansing (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Bonnie Lateiner (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - David Lehman (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Louise Landes Levy (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Bill (Zonko) Little (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Giancarlo (Nino) Locatelli (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Tim Longville (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Lewis MacAdams (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Phoebe [Blackie] MacAdams (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Charles Macaulay (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Nathaniel Mackey (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Gerard Malanga (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Bruce Marcus (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Marin Arts Council (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Dadi Mariotti (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Daphne Marlatt (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - John Martone (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Gail + David Matlin (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Vance Maverick (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bernadette Mayer (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Michael McClure (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Elizabeth McKague (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - William McPheron (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Rob Melton (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - David Meltzer (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sarah Menefee, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Sarah Menefee, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Sarah Menefee, 1994-1998 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Sarah Menefee, 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Sarah Menefee, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - [Jack] Micheline (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - David Miller (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Jean Monod, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jean Monod, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Jean Monod, 1998-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - John Montgomery (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - John Moritz (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Eric Mottram (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Eileen Myler (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Paul Naylon (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Hoa Nguyen (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Gerald Nicosia (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Jim Nisbet (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Alice Notley (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Arthur Okamura (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Jeni Olin (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Charles Olson (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Michael Ondaatje (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Kevin Opstedal (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Ron Padgett (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Clement Padin (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Michael Palmer (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Sherman Paul (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Frank Peters (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Simon Pettet (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Peter Philpott (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Poets House (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Jean Portante (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - David Posner (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Rita + Giam Pozzi [Rita Degli Esposti] (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Michael Price (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Jeremy Prynne (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - George Quasha (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Querini Stampalin (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Jean Radoslovich (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Stephen Ratcliffe (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Tom Raworth, 1975-1984 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Tom Raworth, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tom Raworth, 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Tom Raworth, 1990-1994 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tom Raworth, 1995-2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Tom Raworth, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Vanessa Renwick (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Antonio Ria (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Peter Riley (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - David Ritz (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - David Thomas Roberts (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Kit Robinson (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Judith Roche (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Andres Rodriguez, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Andres Rodriguez, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Andres Rodriguez, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Andres Rodriguez, 1993, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Bob Rose (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Remington Rose (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Bernard Rosenthal (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Charles Ross (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Tina Rotenberg (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Esther Roth (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Michael Rumaker (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Joe Safdie (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Hassan Salame-Sarkis (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Ed Sanders, 1966-1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Ed Sanders, 1975-1980 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Ed Sanders, 1981-1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Ed Sanders, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Aram Saroyan (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Leslie Scalopino (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Bill Scharf, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Bill Scharf, 1976-1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Philipp Schiemann (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Phyllix Segura (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Keith Shein (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Aaron Shurin (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Karl Siegler (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Cedar Sigo (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Richard Silberg (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Joseph Simas (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Gretchen Dow Simpson (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - John Sinclair (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Dale Smith, 1994-1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Dale Smith, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Dale Smith, 2000-2002 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Pat Smith (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Roger Snell (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Louisa Solano (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - William Spanos (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - George Stanley (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Charles Stein (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Tina Stolz (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - David Levi Strauss (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Colin Stuart (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Rachel Sussman (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Nathaniel Tarn (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Warren Tallman (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - John Temple (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Susan Thackrey (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Sharon (Fawcett) Thesen, 1974-1990 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sharon (Fawcett) Thesen, 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sharon (Fawcett) Thesen, 1995-2002 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sharon (Fawcett) Thesen, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - John Thorpe (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Antonella Tomaino (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - John Tranter (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Lyn Tranter (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Nanos Valaoritis (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Allen Van Newkirk (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Dario Villa (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Marta Pellis Villa (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Fred Wah (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Anne Waldman (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Christophe Wall-Romana (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Lewis Warsh (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Barrett Walten (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Philip Whalen (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Derryll White (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - John Wieners, 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - John Wieners, 1970-1974 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Lynne Wildey (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Michael Wilding (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - John Wlkinson (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Michael Wolfe (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Gregory Wood (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Hanford Woods (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Geoff Young (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Daniel Zimmerman (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence 1988 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Outgoing Correspondence
    - Douglas McNaughton, outgoing to Charles Ross (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Louis Patler: incoming correspondence re. NCOC Poetics (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Business/Official correspondence
    - Outgoing letters recommendation for Duncan McNaughton, 1986-1996 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Series 2: New College of California
  - New College of California: "Yanagi," May 1974 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - New College of California: "Convivio: A Journal of Poetics," 1983 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - New College of California: drafts of program catalog, 1980-1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - New College of California: catalogs + announcements, 1980-1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - New College of California: catalogs 1980-1983, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - New College of California: Fall 2000 Course guide (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - New College of California: Notice, Asphaleios, Lynne Wildey's notes (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - New College of California: "Out of Me," MA Poetics Thesis, 1982 by Aaron Shurin (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - New College of California: McNaughton at New College, 1974-1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - New College of California: ephemera (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - New College of California: McNaughton's draft of Curriculum (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - New College of California: McNaughton Photographs: New College, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - New College of California: "Person in Poetry: 'You' Papers" (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - New College of California: "Person in Poetry: 'We' Papers" (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - New College of California: "Book II: Person in Poetry 'We'" (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - New College of California: "Book II section 2" (we/they) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - New College Poetics: Jack Winkler transcripts on Sappho, fall 1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - New College Poetics: Jack Winkler transcripts on Sappho, fall 1983 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - New College of California: "La Bela Semblansa," Carl Grundberg, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - New College of California: Poetics Program grant info, 1984-1986 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - New College of California: Dawn Michelle Baude (rough draft w/ corrections) (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - New College of California: Poetics - "The Grammar of Dictation," Dawn Kolokithas (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - New College of California: Poetics Program, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - New College of California: Poetics Program student/faculty responses toDiPrima letter, summer 1985 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - New College of California: Poetics Program, budget (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - New College of California: Grenier information (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - New College of California: Poetics Program proposal, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Writings/Publications/Drafts
  - "From feathers to Iron," 1987 published (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - "From feathers to Iron," misc. John Clark correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "From feathers to Iron," lecture transcriptions w/ John Clarke (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - "From feathers to Iron," lecture transcript w/ corrections (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "From Feathers to Iron," drafts + Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "From Feathers to Iron," drafts (Box 22, Folders 2-6)
  - Drafts + Scrawls Buffalo 1972 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Drafts + Scrawls Buffalo ca. 1972-74 N.H. - Bolinas (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Drafts + Scrawls N.H. 1973, Bolinas 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Drafts + Scrawls [1973-1975] Bolinas (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Drafts + Scrawls [1973-1977] Bolinas (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Drafts + Scrawls Bolinas ca. 1974-75 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Drafts + Scrawls [1976-1979] Bolinas (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Drafts + Scrawls 1978-1979 [Bolinas] (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Drafts + Scrawls 1986-88 Santa Cruz (Box 23, Folders 7-8)
  - Unpublished Mss. ca. 1974-1979 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - UC Extension San Francisco Spring 1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 19 March 1999 The Koerner Lecture Series (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 291 a film 1990-1991 El Cerrito (Box 24, Folders 3-4)
  - Poetry Flash [1988], Barrett Walter [1985] (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Preface to Catalog for Pierre Coupey's Tokyo Exhibit Notations [1998] (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - The Apparition Buffalo March 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to Robt. Duncan's reading 9 Nov. 1978 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - One of Melville's Churches #7 Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Introductions to Emerson, Hawthorne for Woodsworth Editions London [1996-1997] (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Literary essays, Book Reviews 1969-1988 (Box 24, Folders 11-12)
  - Comnenvement Mid-to late 70s to 1980 summer. Attempt at Book manuscript (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Prose Drafts 60s/80s Unpublished envelope (Box 24, Folders 14-15)
  - Early Poems - Indian Island 1966 - 1970 Buffalo (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Dream (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Poems 1966-1973 from Brookline-Indian Island - Buffalo - Antrim (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Fellowship + grant applications 1992-93 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Fellowship + grant applications 1993-1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks 1971-1977 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folders 5-6)
  - Notebooks 1983-1987 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks 1983-1987 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks 1988 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks 1989-1992 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Trans. of Franco Beltrametti Eleven Takes Plus One (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Translation of Jean Monod's Tiens la Vie (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Antonio Ria The Spirit of the "Tribe of Poets" 1996 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Dario Villa Immagini Volubili Voluble Images 1996 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Poem, 28 Aug. 1995 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Announcements/flyers for readings 1974-2003 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Notes/Prose [Jan. - June 1994] notebook (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Save Chile notes from 1990 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - 1987 Santa Cruz UCSC Course notes Fall 1987 Intro to Amer. Poetry Notebook (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Kicking the Feather drafts + pub. staff. (Box 27, Folders 2-4)
  - Kicking the Feather Giannis Artwork (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Another set of circumstance [1996] - [14 Jun? 97] (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Another Set of Circumstance drafts of poems out-takes (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Singularite' progressive Ms./Proofs (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - The Wrapped Church - Ms. drafts (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Atlanta [1995-1997] (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - A Passage of St. Devil (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - A Passage of Saint Devil Working Ms. 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Sumeriana (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Sumeriana (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Shit on My Shoes drafts of Work in it Ca. 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Shit on My Shoes drafts 1973-1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - A MS. Shit on My Shoes Working Manuscript 1979 (Box 28, Folders 8-9)
  - Pacific Slope Carbon (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Pacific Slope (Carbon) First Typescript (Box 29, Folders 2-3)
  - Black Spoon drafts + notes and other Valparaiso Stuff (Box 29, Folders 4-5)
  - Valparaiso - typescript off disc w/ typescript of 'Black Spoon' (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Valparaiso (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Valparaiso (Box 29, Folder 8)